Diana K. Perez Lopez

Pre-Doctoral Fellow, Yale Economics Department

diana.perezlopez@yale.edu

https://dianakperezlopez.github.io/

Profile

I am a Pre-Doctoral Fellow at the Yale Economics Department and Economic Growth Center, working with Professor Orazio Attanasio on early childhood development and alternative ways to interpret the magnitude of Randomized Controlled Trials' impacts.

EDUCATION

| Spring 2021 | M.A. Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia | |
|-------------|---|--|
| | cum laude, GPA 4.72 out of 5, ranked 2 out of 38 | |
| | Thesis: "'Am I not good at it or am I not good at all?' STEM gender gaps in | |
| | higher education." (Grade: 5 out of 5, coded as Approved for COVID-19) | |
| Spring 2019 | B.A. Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia | |
| | Minor in Management, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia | |

Awards

| 2021 | Placed in the top 3% of the previous 5 years of graduates in the M.A. in economics, |
|------|---|
| | Universidad de los Andes, Colombia (cum laude) |
| 2018 | Placed in the top 1% in the Colombian higher education examinations (Saber Pro) |
| 2014 | Placed in the top 2% in the Colombian high school education examinations (Saber |
| | 11) |

RELATED ADVANCED COURSEWORK

Yale University: Real Analysis (A); Universidad de los Andes, Colombia: Advanced Econometrics (5 out of 5) · Econometrics and Machine Learning (5 out of 5) · Long-Run Advanced Macroeconomics (4.6 out of 5) · Advanced Microeconomics Game Theory (4.5 out of 5) ·

Research Experience

Department of Economics and Economic Growth Center, Yale University

Pre-Doctoral/Postgraduate Fellow

Aug. 2021 - Present Principal investigator: Orazio Attanasio

Research Assistant

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021 Principal investigator: Orazio Attanasio

Department of Economics and CEDE, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Research Assistant

| May 2019 - Mar. 2021 | Principal investigator: | Raquel Bernal |
|-----------------------|-------------------------|---------------|
| Oct. 2018 - Jun. 2019 | Principal investigator: | Fabio Sanchez |
| Jan. 2018 - Dec. 2020 | Principal investigator: | Diego Amador |

Department of Economics, Princeton University

Research Assistant

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020 Principal investigator: Micaela Sviatschi

Work in Progress

[&]quot;'Am I not good at it or am I not good at all?' STEM gender gaps in higher education."

"GRE waving and diversity on graduate school programs"

"Remedial courses to complement scholarship programs for low-income students"

"Price regulation of contraceptives, teenage pregnancy, and abortion"

"Measuring Impacts of Early Childhood Development Interventions." With *Orazio Attanasio*, Sarah Cattan, Sharon Wolf, Matias Placencio-Castro, and Marta Rubio-Codina.

"Estimating the Production Function of Human Capital in India." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Costas Meghir*, *Pamela Jervis*, and Alessandro Toppeta.

"The Role of Maternal and Paternal Inputs on Child Development: Evidence from a Randomized Controlled Trial in Rwanda." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Theresa Betancourt*, *Sarah K. G. Jensen*, and *Matias Placencio-Castro*.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Spring 2019 - Spring 2021 Advanced Econometrics (masters); Prof. Raquel Bernal and

Prof. Manuel Fernandez

Fall 2019 - Fall 2020 Behavioral Economics (undergraduate); *Prof. Andres Moya*

Spring 2019 - Summer 2019 Forecasting (masters); Prof. Daniel Wills

Summer 2019 Advanced Impact Evaluation on Complex Models (masters);

Prof. Sergio Urzua

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Fall 2017 Econometrics (undergraduate)

Spring 2017 - Fall 2017 Integral Calculus and Probability (undergraduate)

Spring 2017 Probability and Statistics 1 (undergraduate)

SUMMER SCHOOLS AND COMMUNITY WORK

| Nov. 2019 | RIDGE Summer School in Economics |
|-----------|---|
| Sep. 2019 | Community work: Translation of "CORE: The Economy" to Spanish |
| Fall 2018 | Community work, "Programa Progresa Fenicia": School tutoring for low- |
| | income school-aged children |

SKILLS

| Stata and LATEX | Advanced | R and Matlab | Intermediate | HTML | Beginner |
|-----------------|----------|--------------|---------------|-----------|----------|
| Duduu ana Lipar | riavanca | it and mada | intollicataco | 11 1 1111 | Dogimioi |

LANGUAGES

| English | Fluent | Spanish | Native |
|---------|--------|---------|--------|
| | | | |

REFERENCES

Orazio Attanasio
Cowles Professor of Economics, Yale University
orazio.attanasio@yale.edu

Raquel Bernal
President and Full Professor of Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia
rbernal@uniandes.edu.co

Costas Meghir
Douglas A Warner III Professor of Economics, Yale University
c.meghir@yale.edu

Diego Amador
Research Scientist, Texas Policy Lab, Rice University
diego.amador.o@gmail.com